Dennis Kamau



dmkamau475@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/denmau



+254759360020



https://denmau.me

Summary

TensorFlow Certified Machine Learning Engineer with frontend and backend skills. Today, I am focusing on delivering APIs that scale. Familiar with the Software Development patterns, Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) and Agile Methodologies.

My skills span from software design, building mobile applications with Flutter and Java, Web frontends with Vue.js, and the backend with Django or PHP. Experienced with containers (Docker), API integration, and setting up deployment pipelines on Heroku, Amazon Web Services (AWS), and Google Cloud Platform (GCP). For Databases, I am comfortable with MySQL, PostgreSQL, and Firebase. I am a huge fan of Jetbrains IDEs. If you catch me outside of work, I'm an adventurous traveler and an avid lover of basketball!

Experience

Software Engineer

Startappz Limited

Oct 2021 - Present (1 month +)

- Deploying and Managing Linux servers on the cloud.
- Developing and Maintaining Deployment pipelines for various projects.
- Building and Architecting Web and Mobile Applications, along with API integrations and Database Management.

Junior Web Developer (PHP and Flutter)

Startappz Limited

Jul 2021 - Sep 2021 (3 months)

- Developed bespoke Web applications with PHP, JavaScript, Ajax, and HTML/CSS.
- Developed Mobile applications with Flutter, often while collaborating with a UI/UX Designer.
- Developed beautiful UI for internal tools and automating backend tasks.
- API integrations and Database management.
- Helped with System Architecture for software solutions.

Junior Machine Learning Engineer

Omdena

May 2021 - Jul 2021 (3 months)

- Reduced business expenses immensely by implementing computer vision with OpenCV.
- Built and optimized Machine Learning models with TensorFlow.
- Conceptualized APIs to serve ML models to edge devices.
- Collaborated with a remote team on Slack, with weekly meetings with the business owner.

zuri. Backend Developer Intern

Zuri Team, Inc.

Mar 2021 - Jun 2021 (4 months)

• Work on Full-Stack web projects with Python Django.

- Collaborate with other interns on projects over slack as a Backend Developer.
- Worked on a site that links drivers to a mechanic from any part of Nigeria!
- Used tools such as Python, Django, and SQL.

Frontend Developer, BuildForSDG Challenge 2020

Andela

Jul 2020 - Nov 2020 (5 months)

- Collaborated in an agile remote team to innovate on real-world, locally and relevant solutions focused on the Sustainable Development Goals(SDGs).
- worked on a team project to connect farmers to consumers.
- Prepared visual presentations for team meetings.
- Used HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap and jQuery.

Education



eMobilis Mobile Technology Institute

Bootcamp, Android App Development

2021 - 2021

- · Android Java | Firebase | SQLite
- · Location | Google Maps | APIs | Networking

eMobilis Mobile Technology Institute

Full Stack Web Development bootcamp, Computer Software and Media Applications 2021 - 2021

Gave me a very firm foundation in

PHP | JavaScript | HTML/CSS

Apps:Lab

21C Skills Training, Software Engineering

Oct 2020 - Feb 2021

- Strong Computer Science principles and Data Structures & Algorithms.
- Learned the importance of Testing and how to go about it, with some bit of info on test automation.

Licenses & Certifications



DeepLearning.Al TensorFlow Developer Specialization - DeepLearning.Al

QP3343SDDDGG



TensorFlow Developer Certificate - TensorFlow Certificate Program 38536516